A Guide to the Sara Teasdale Collection
University of Virginia Library
- LETTERS
  - Rufus Rockwell Wilson, Seattle, Washington, to Sara Teasdale, c/o G. P. Putnam's Sons, New York, New York, 1911 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting information from her for his "calendar of the poets"
  - Charles E. Savage, G. P. Putnam's Sons, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 16; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    concerning an enquiry on her first volume,
  - Joseph Benson Gilder, Hudson Terminal, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 19; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    congratulating her after seeing the review of her book, Helen of Troy..., in the St. Louis Times, written on an announcement of new employment with Hornblower & Weeks
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1911 Dec 21; APCS (Box Box 4)
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 22; ALS, w/env. (Box Box 4)
    concerning the Poetry Society of America, and mentioning certain persons -- Cale Young Rice, Josephine Peabody, Percy Mackaye--planning to attend their annual dinner
  - Louis Untermeyer, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 23; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    writing in answer to her note about his review of
    and further critiquing the poetry as he would have if given more space in
    The International
    , and commenting that the attitude in the love lyrics is that of a woman
  - George Sterling, Carmel, California, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 25; ALS, 4 p. on 4 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for the book of poems,
    , finding her lyrics "poignant and pertinent," commenting on several of his personal favorites, and giving a brief comment on Rudyard Kipling
  - Fannie L. Richey, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 26; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    enclosing a letter from a friend praising Sara Teasdale's book of poems,
    and commenting on Teasdale's understanding
  - George Sylvester Viereck, The Viereck Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 26; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    asking the basis for her poem, "Sappho"
  - George S. Johns, St. Louis Post-Dispatch, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Missouri, 1911 Dec 28; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing gratitude for the copy of her book,
    , and commenting on her gift of song
  - Orrick Johns, Madison Square, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 30; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    commenting that her "The Poor House" was the only poem read at the meeting of the Poetry Society of America
  - Ella M. Kricklaus, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1911 Dec 31; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    saying she has read her book,
    , and writing of having the same dream twice
  - Josephine McGill, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Jan 3; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to set to music her poem "When Love Comes Singing to his Heart"
  - George Sylvester Viereck, The Viereck Publishing Company, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Jan 3; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    revealing himself as an admirer of her work and putting her in a class with himself
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Jan 4; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    receiving her acceptance to the annual dinner of the Poetry Society of America
  - Rupert Henry Whitcomb to Sara Teasdale, 1912 Jan 6; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for her effort to go to the Guild and for allowing him to use her poems in a musical setting
  - Elizabeth McCracken, Editor, Home Progress, Houghton Mifflin Company, Boston, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1912 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for `The Book of Poems' and sending a circular of
    Home Progress
    along with some literary notes
  - W. W. Tulloch("Orion"), Perth, The Club House, St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Jan 15; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    sending a review and thanking her for the charming poems
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Jan 16; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    writing that he will run Marion Cummings Stanley's article about her poems, and congratulating her on her move to New York
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Frank George, Hutchinson, Kansas, 1912 Jan 16; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    commenting on his book of poems and preparing for her move to New York
  - George Sylvester Viereck, The Waldorf-Astoria, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Jan; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    praising her as the "most gifted of the lyric girls," also signed by Richard LeGallienne and B. Russell Herts
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 2; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    appreciative of her book,
    [Helen of Troy...]
  - Frederick Oakes Sylvester, Central High School, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 3; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    taking the liberty of sending his edition of poems, and expressing his delight in her two books
    [Sonnets to Duse...]
    and
  - George Sterling, Carmel, California, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 12; ALS, 2 p.on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    sending her a copy of his book, commenting on her style and on his own, asking if she knows Zoe Akins and writing that she sent him her book of poems, and discussing the beauty of Carmel
  - Dugald Stewart Walker, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 14; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    showing his gratitude for her book,
    , and inviting her to tea
  - Blanche Shoemaker Wagstaff, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 16; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing her "more poignant" pleasure in Sara Teasdale's poems after meeting her
  - Anna Branch, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 17; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for her book
    and admiring its style, and giving a message from Edith Thomas
  - Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1912 Feb 19; APCS, w/env. (Box Box 4)
  - Curtis Hidden Page, Columbia University, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 23; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    acknowledging receipt of her book
    and expressing his pleasure in reading it, and giving a critique of many of the poems
  - Ethel Peyser, Editor, Good Housekeeping Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 23; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    praising her poem, "The Poorhouse" and confirming luncheon plans
  - Gertrude Cawein, The National Arts Club, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 25; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for the inscribed copy of her book
  - Theodosia Garrison Faulks, Elizabeth, New Jersey, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 26; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing her delight in seeing Sara Teasdale's name in so many magazines, and requesting to have tea with her
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 28; TLS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for her letter of appreciation for Louis Untermeyer's poem, and commenting on George Sylvester Viereck, B. Russell Herts, and Orrick Johns
  - Edward J. Wheeler, Editorial Rooms, Current Literature, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Feb 29; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    commenting on her sweet letter and on "the twilight of Poetry"
  - Alexander Harvey, Editorial Rooms, Current Literature, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 1; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    finding her genius in the pages of
  - W. W. Tulloch("Orion"), Murray House, Perth, St. Andrews, Fife, Scotland, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 1; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    commenting on the review of her book,
    , which he previously sent, written on a flyer about himself entitled "A .... Journalistic Jubilee.. ."
  - Wilfred Funk, Editorial Rooms, The Literary Digest, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 8; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for the note and book of verse
  - Campbell Mason, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 9; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    referring to her poem, "Four Winds," as "deep, refreshing, and ... so cruelly true," and waiting to pick up a copy of her volume
  - Joyce Kilmer, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 12; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    writing that he will sign his name to the sonnet [as requested], intending to return
    The Younger Choir
    in person instead of by mail, inviting her and Dugald Stewart Walker to visit one evening, and expecting Aline and Kenton to call on her the following day
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 19; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    requesting her to "contribute an original complimentary poem in honor of Browning's centenary" for an article in the
    Boston Transcript
    on May 4, honoring Robert Browning, and mentioning Carman Bliss, Edwin Markham, and Edwin Arlington Robinson as being among those who have already consented
  - Harper & Brothers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 21; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    concerning a request through their London office from Messrs. Chappell & Co., Ltd., to publish her poem, "Pierrot," with a musical setting
  - Clayton Hamilton, The Players, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 24; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing his pleasure in receiving her book of poems
    , and looking forward to meeting her one day
  - Arthur Guiterman, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 24; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing his pleasure in reading her book
    , and commenting on her writing improvement
  - Laurence J. Gomme, The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publisher, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 27; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    looking forward to having her inscribe his copy of her book of poems
  - Nana Wilcox Putnam, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 28; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing her great pleasure at receiving her letter and book
    , and discussing friendship
  - Josie Grevé Oppenheim, Walforf-Astoria, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Mar 30; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for her book of poems
    , and returning her kindness with a copy of her own novel
  - John Curtis Underwood, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Mar 31; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    wanting to exchange his book,
    The Iron Muse
    , autographed, for any one of her books, and explaining the concept of his book, enclosing two of his poems, "Reno" and "The Star"
  - Leonard D. Abbott, The Current Literature Publishing Co., New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Apr 6; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    acknowledging her kindness in sending the inscribed copy of her book
    , and expressing his thoughts after meeting her, with enclosure on "The Modern School"
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, Charles Scribner's Sons Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Apr 6; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for a copy of her volume of poems,
    , and commenting on her clarity of poetic ideas
  - Anna Hinrichs, Secretary, The Papyrus Club of St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Apr 10; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    concerning the club's thirty-fourth meeting and enclosing a program
  - Editor (Ferdinand Earle), "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Apr 25; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    requesting "new treasures" for "The Lyric Year," and referring to a poem in process addressed to Sara Teasdale
  - Editor, "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 3; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    commenting on his verse coming slowly and on finishing his poem dedicated to Sara Teasdale by a year or so, and writing to ask if she "will not find the rare inspiration on the sea," in reference to her sailing to Europe
  - Editor, "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publishers, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 3; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    intending to extend the poetry contest and commenting on her wanting to sell her poem
  - Idress Head, Librarian, Missouri Historical Society, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 8; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting her to autograph a recently purchased book of her writings
  - Josephine Hilty Abramson, Los Angeles, California, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 13; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to use two of her poems in musical settings
  - Josephine McGill, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 18; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    requesting to use another one of her poems, "Less than the Cloud to the Wind," in a musical setting, and sending the title notice about "When Love Comes Singing"
  - Cecile Barnes, Brooklyn, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 May 25; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to use her verse, "At Night," in a musical setting
  - John G. Neihardt, Bancroft, Nebraska, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 June 2; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    requesting biographical data, a photograph and review copies from her publishers for an upcoming series of special articles on American poets that he is going to undertake in his new capacity as head of a literary department in
    The Minneapolis Journal
  - John G. Neihardt, Bancroft, Nebraska, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 June 25; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
    following up on his last letter since he has not heard from her, and naming some contributors to the article
  - Williamina Parrish, New York, New York, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 June 28; APCS (Box Box 4)
    repeating a prior request
  - Jessie T. Pease to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 July 12; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to use her poem, "Pierrot," in a musical setting
  - Sara Teasdale, Florence, Italy, to Vine Colby, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 July 12; APCS (Box Box 4)
  - Oswald Rimmer, London, England, to Harper & Brothers, New York, New York, 1912 July 18; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    requesting permission to put Sara Teasdale's verse, "Song," to music
  - John G. Neihardt, Bancroft, Nebraska, to Sara Teasdale, Palace Hotel, Monteverioc, Suisse (Switzerland), 1912 July 19; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    thanking her for the letter and copy of
    , trying to express the sincerity of his motive in doing the project, and praising her blank verse poems
  - Gertrude Cate, Wellesley, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1912 July 20; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    praising her volumes,
    , and desiring to obtain a copy of the latter
  - Editor (Ferdinand Earle?), "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publisher, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Italy, 1912 Aug 14; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 4)
    acknowledging receipt of her songs and letters, praising the "rapture and delicacy" of her "From the Sea," and mentioning the poetry contest
  - W. F. Melton, Emory College, Oxford, Georgia, to Sara Teasdale, c/o The Century Magazine, New York, New York, 1912 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    passing on a compliment from Ella Wheeler Willcox and requesting a list of her books along with the publishers' names
  - May W. Dorman, Indianapolis, Indiana, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Sep 16; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    asking for Jessie Belle Rittenhouse's address in order to express her interest in the Poetry Society of America, and praising Sara Teasdale's verses
  - Mitchell Kennerley, "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publisher, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1912 Sep 21; TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    accepting her poem, "I Shall Not Care," for publication
  - Editor, "The Lyric Year," The Forum, Mitchell Kennerley Publisher, 1912 Sep 24; ALS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 4)
    expressing his pleasure in Mitchell Kennerley's acceptance of her poem for "The Lyric Year"
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Oct 16; TNS, 1 p., w/enclosure (Box Box 5)
    sending "a few lines of opinion upon your verse..."
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, Winthrop, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, 1912 Oct 17; ALS, 2 p. on 2 l., w/enclosure (Box Box 5)
    concerning her request for his review of
    and his own editorship of "The Poetry Journal"
  - Jessie Belle Rittenhouse, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1912 Oct 22; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    writing a brief opinion of
  - Thomas Augustine Daly, Germantown, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, 1912 Nov 29; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    admiring her and thanking her for her kind thoughts
  - Robert Underwood Johnson, Editor, The Century Magazine, Union Square, New York, 1912 Dec 2; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting Sara Teasdale's poem, "Off Capri"
  - Helen Bullis, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1912 Dec 5; ALS, 3 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    commenting on the honesty of her poetry, mentioning her review of
    , and asking if she knows George Buchanan Fife
  - Percy MacKaye, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Dec 4; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
  - Fannie Stearns Davis, Pittsfield, Massachusetts, 1912 Dec 5; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    expressing her admiration for Sara Teasdale's poetry and her gratitude for Teasdale noticing her writing
  - William Marion Reedy, Editor, The Mirror, St. Louis, Missouri, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Dec 9; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting her Christmas poem and requesting a review of John Hall Wheelock's book of poetry
  - John Hall Wheelock, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1912 Dec 10; AL, 3 p. on 2 l., w/enclosures, w/env. (Box Box 5)
    confessing to be a great admirer of her poetry and
    , thanking her for her note, and enclosing a circular of his new book,
    The Beloved Adventure
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Bruce M. Stanley, Tucson, Arizona, 1912 Dec 21; APCS (Box Box 5)
  - W. W. Tulloch, Perth, The Club House, St. Andrews, Fife, to Sara Teasdale, 1912; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
  - Robert Bridges, Scribner's Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Jan 13; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting "Sappho" for future publication
  - Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, to Frank George, 1913 Jan 15; ANS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    thanking him for the booklet
  - Bliss Carman, New Canaan, Connecticut, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Jan 20; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l, w/enclosure, w/env. (Box Box 5)
    thanking her for the book and giving a glowing opinion of
  - Editor, Lippincott's Monthly Magazine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Jan 25; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting "The Hour," with a slight change in the second stanza
  - Editor, Lippincott's Monthly Magazine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Feb 1; TLS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    returning her poem, "The Hour," since she rejects the change and apologizing for a printing error
  - Edna St. Vincent Millay, Grand Central Station, New York, to Sara Teasdale, New York, New York, 1913 Feb 11; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    looking forward to meeting an old friend (Sara Teasdale) for the first time
  - Cale Young Rice, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Feb 11; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    thanking her for the volume,
  - Editor, Lippincott's Monthly Magazine, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, 1913 Feb 12; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    reaching an agreement concerning her poem, "The Hour"
  - Lawrence Gilman, Managing Editor, Harper's Weekly, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, St. Louis, Missouri, 1913 Feb 13; TLS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    accepting her two poems, "Song" and "Gifts"
  - Cale Young Rice, Louisville, Kentucky, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, 1913 Mar 3; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    expressing his having the "true pleasure of finding a heart-full of real love lyrics" and praising her work
  - William Stanley Braithwaite, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, 1913 Mar 5; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    accepting two of her poems for
    The Poetry Journal
    , and mentioning a tete-a-tete with [Alfred] Noyes
  - H. L. Mencken, Baltimore, Maryland, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, New York, New York, TLS, 1 p., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    commenting that her work is just what the
    Smart Set
    needs
  - John Sanburn Phillips, Editor, The American Magazine, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Mar 19; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    praising her as the best "writer of delicate lyrics" and commenting on some of her verse in
  - Merle St. Croix Wright, New York, New York, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Mar 21; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 5)
    sending a tribute to her muse and expressing his enjoyment of her visit
  - Nathan Haskell Dole, Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts, to Sara Teasdale, Hotel Martha Washington, 1913 Mar 28; ALS, 4 p. on 1 l., w/env. (Box Box 5)
    praising her volume and apologizing for his delay in writing due to his busy schedule
  - Harriet Monroe, Editor, Poetry: A Magazine of Verse, Chicago, Illinois, to Sara Teasdale, 1913 Mar 31; ALS, 2 p. on 1 l. (Box Box 5)
    keeping six of her poems for publication and suggesting a few changes